<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gear on Erik Johannes Husom</title>
    <link>https://erikjohannes.no/categories/gear/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gear on Erik Johannes Husom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 13:23:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://erikjohannes.no/categories/gear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the temperature on a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20201110-raspberry-pi-temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 13:23:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20201110-raspberry-pi-temperature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have for several months been hosting my own cloud services using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nextcloud.com/&#34;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt; on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/raspberry-pi-4-model-b/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi
4&lt;/a&gt;. At first I
was using a plastic case for the Pi, but I quickly figured out that I had to
use something else, as the temperature was constantly in the range of 70-75
degrees Celsius, which I figured was too high when it is supposed to be an
always-on system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purchased an &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepihut.com/products/xl-raspberry-pi-4-heatsink&#34;&gt;extra large heat
sink&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepihut.com/products/cluster-case-for-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;cluster
case with fans&lt;/a&gt; in
order to reduce the temperature, but I was unsure of how much it would help,
and also whether the fan was as quiet as the product description claimed.
The delivery of the items took some weeks, so in the meantime I used a stack of
coins placed on top of the processing unit, which worked remarkably well (at
least compared to my expectations): The temperature was reduced with about
15-20 degrees Celsius.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20201110-raspberry-pi-temperature/coin-stack.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Using a coin stack as a heat sink.&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Using a coin stack as a heat sink.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After attaching the heat sink to the Pi, and then installing the Pi in the
cluster case and mounting the fan, the temperature of the Pi dropped to the
range of 30-35 degrees Celsius when running a Nextcloud server. This was much
better than I expected, and the fans hardly make any noise at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20201110-raspberry-pi-temperature/cluster.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Two Raspberry Pis installed in a cluster case, with the old plastic case nextto it.&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Two Raspberry Pis installed in a cluster case, with the old plastic case next
to it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also tried a &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepihut.com/products/aluminium-armour-heatsink-case-for-raspberry-pi-4&#34;&gt;heatsink
case&lt;/a&gt;
for another one of my Pis, and the temperature is reduced by about 20-25
degrees Celsius, so that is not a bad option either.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keychain bit holder</title>
      <link>https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 17:58:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got a small keychain multitool called True Utility Fishface, which
amongst other things has a bit driver on it. It is basically just a hex-formed
hole in the multitool, and can be used to drive any sort of standard
screwdriver bit. The Fishface also comes with special &lt;em&gt;dual bit&lt;/em&gt;, which is
fastened to the multitool with to small rubber bands, and consists of two sizes
of the cross-point/Phillips screwdriver head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/02.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The True Utility Fishface.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/03.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Fishface with the dual bit in the driver.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main advantages of carrying a multitool with a bit driver is that it
can be adapted for your specific needs. For me it is very useful to carry hex
bits, specifically the 4mm and 5mm, since those are commonly used on just about
everything on bikes. But how to carry the extra bits I need? One nifty solution
would be to drill a hole in the bits, and then they could be fastened directly
on the keychain ring, but I do not have the kind of tools needed for that
operation. While doing some brainstorming, my eyes landed on a pen on my desk,
and suddenly I realized that the shell of that pen was the perfect size for
housing a couple of bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/04.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;An identical pen to the one I used for making the bit holder, alongside the
finished &amp;ldquo;product&amp;rdquo;. The two items are aligned, so you can see where I cut off
the top and bottom of the pen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After gently sawing the plastic of the pen in the appropriate plazes, using a
serrated knife blade, the remaining cylinder could fit the two bits I want to
carry around. In one end I fastened a keychain ring with some duct tape, and
the other end is closed by screwing the small remaining piece of the bottom
part of the pen into place. The bottom part of the bit holder is actually open,
but the hole is to small for the bits to fall out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/05.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/06.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exact process of making the bit holder will differ
slightly depending on the pen you are using, but it is anyway a quick and cheap
way of making a small bit holder with things you most likely already have in
your house.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
