<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>diy on Erik Johannes Husom</title>
    <link>https://erikjohannes.no/tags/diy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in diy on Erik Johannes Husom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 17:58:42 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://erikjohannes.no/tags/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Keychain Bit Holder and keychain multitool</title>
      <link>https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 17:58:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got a small keychain multitool called True Utility Fishface, which
amongst other things has a bit driver on it. It is basically just a hex-formed
hole in the multitool, and can be used to drive any sort of standard
screwdriver bit. The Fishface also comes with special &lt;em&gt;dual bit&lt;/em&gt;, which is
fastened to the multitool with to small rubber bands, and consists of two sizes
of the cross-point/Phillips screwdriver head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/02.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The True Utility Fishface.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/03.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Fishface with the dual bit in the driver.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main advantages of carrying a multitool with a bit driver is that it
can be adapted for your specific needs. For me it is very useful to carry hex
bits, specifically the 4mm and 5mm, since those are commonly used on just about
everything on bikes. But how to carry the extra bits I need? One nifty solution
would be to drill a hole in the bits, and then they could be fastened directly
on the keychain ring, but I do not have the kind of tools needed for that
operation. While doing some brainstorming, my eyes landed on a pen on my desk,
and suddenly I realized that the shell of that pen was the perfect size for
housing a couple of bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/04.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The original pen alongside the finished bit holder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After gently sawing the plastic of the pen in the appropriate plazes, using a
serrated knife blade, the remaining cylinder could fit the two bits I want to
carry around. In one end I fastened a keychain ring with some duct tape, and
the other end is closed by screwing the bottom part of the pen into place. The
bottom part of the bit holder is actually open, but the hole is to small for
the bits to fall out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/05.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://erikjohannes.no/posts/20200924-keychain-bit-holder/06.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exact process of making the bit holder will differ
slightly depending on the pen you are using, but it is anyway a quick and cheap
way of making a small bit holder with things you most likely already have in
your house.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
